Guide to the Publications Office, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Publications Office, Yale University Library, records
1965-1979
RU 755
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16.25
(13 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, working files, orders, printed material, and financial records of the Publications Office, Yale University Library. Topics include the publication projects, Research Libraries Group, and Systems Office projects.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-C (YRG 32-C), Records of Yale University Library departments and offices.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, working files, orders, printed material, and financial records of the Publications Office, Yale University Library. Topics include the publication projects, Research Libraries Group, and Systems Office projects.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Academic libraries; Libraries -- Publishing; Research Libraries Group; Yale University. Library
- Records, 1920-1978; Accession 1989-A-055
  - From other institutions-, 1970s (Box 1)
    - handouts (Box 1)
    - policy statements (Box 1)
    - newsletters (Box 1)
  - RLG materials, 1970s (Box 2)
    - standards (Box 2)
    - lists (Box 2)
    - annual reports (Box 2)
    - Sharpe library survey (Box 2)
    - manuals (Box 2)
    - Boards of governors and directors (Box 2)
    - Committees (Box 2)
  - Pubs Office Records, 1940s-1970s (Box 3)
  - folder on their projects (Box 3)
  - Pubs Office Records for ~ this box (Box 4)
  - Ms for "User Requirements" (Box 4)
  - Systems office projects (Box 4)
  - Marc Pilot Project, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Users Handbook (original), 1969 (Box 5)
  - Machine Aided Technical Processing System, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Also lists (Box 5)
      - manuals (Box 5)
      - reports (Box 5)
  - Working files, 1970s (Box 5)
    - reports (Box 5)
    - budgets (Box 5)
    - disbursements (Box 5)
    - accounts (Box 5)
    - lists (Box 5)
    - deposits (Box 5)
  - Order correspondence, 1970s (Box 6)
    - include microfilm orders (Box 6)
      - Invoices (Box 6)
      - Photo orders (Box 6)
  - Financial Journals, 1970s (Box 7)
    - deposit and cash records (Box 7)
    - disbursments, quaterly reports (Box 7)
    - list of publications, 1920s-1930s (Box 7)
    - bills (Box 7)
  - Duplicates of forms (Box 8)
  - cash receipt slips (Box 8)
  - deposits, part time staff (Box 8)
  - Re. promo of publications (Box 8)
  - proposed publications (Box 8)
  - Old records (Box 9)
    - distribution of manuals (Box 9)
    - correspondence, bills, receipts re. projects (Box 9)
    - Questionaire with correspondence re. Buying Y.U. catalog on microfilm (Box 9)
    - Catalog production notes (Box 9)
  - Descriptions of and information on, 1970-1976 (Box 10)
    - Christmas cards (removed for the Yale Greeting Card ColI.) (Box 10)
    - prints (Box 10)
    - drawings (Box 10)
    - maps (Box 10)
  - Microfilm information (Box 11)
    - Publications, MSSA, 1970-1978 (Box 11)
      - lists (Box 11)
      - forms (Box 11)
      - data (Box 11)
      - memoranda (Box 11)
    - Dissertations, 1970-1975 (Box 11)
      - Check sheets (Box 11)
      - Work orders (Box 11)
    - Human Relations Area Files, 1967-1978 (Box 11)
      - file slips (Box 11)
    - RLG Monthly varification slips, 1982 (Box 11)
  - RLG Monthly varification slips, 1980-82 (Box 12–13)